My name's Shinichi Kudo.
اسمي كودو شينتشي
I'm a famous high school detective known throughout the country!
!مُتحرٍّ في الثانوية مشهور في أرجاء البلاد
But I was forced to take a pill by some organization...
...لكن أجبرتني منظمة ما على تجرّع سمٍّ غريب
...and became Conan Edogawa!
!وأصبحت إيدوغاوا كونان
Doesn't matter if I'm small!
!لا يهم صغر بنيتي
My mind's that of a brilliant 17-year-old detective!
!فدماغي ذاك لمُتحرٍّ في السابعة عشر
I can solve cases that not even adults can handle!
!يمكنني حلّ قضايا تستعصي على البالغين حتّى
It's been 3 days since I shrunk.
مضت 3 أيّام مُذ تقلّص جسدي
There still hasn't been any information about the men in black.
لم تظهر أيّ معلومات عن الرجال بالرداء الأسود بعد
But nobody would ask a detective like him for help,
...لكن مع مُتحرّ مثله
much less give him information about those men.
،لن يطلب أحد خدماته في الأصل فكيف يتلقى معلومات عنهم؟
Yoko-san, you're so cute!
!يوكو-تشان، ظريفة جدّاً
Go, go, let's go!
!هيّا، هيّا، هيّا بنا
Come on now, you're too old to be acting like that.
لا يسمح لك عمرك بالتصرف هكذا
You set the example for hopeless men.
أنت أفضل مثال للرجل اليائس
Teitan Elementary School
مدرسة تيتان الابتدائية
2 times 2 is 4.
اثنان ضرب اثنان يساوي 4
2 times 3 is 6.
اثنان ضرب ثلاثة يساوي 6
2 times 4 is 8.
اثنان ضرب أربعة يساوي 8
I can't take this anymore...
...لا أستطيع الاحتمال
Let's walk home together, Conan-kun!
!لنعد للبيت معاً يا كونان-كن
You must feel kind of lonely since you just transferred here, right?
لا بدّ أنك تشعر بالوحدة لانتقالك حديثاً
So, we'll be your friends!
!لذا سنكون أصدقاءك
No, um, I don't really...
...كلا، لستُ حقّاً
Hey, you!
!أنت
Are you saying no to Ayumi-chan?!
!أترفض كلام أيومي-تشان
Violence isn't good, Genta-kun.
العنف ليس حسناً يا غينتا-كن
Shut up! You got a problem with me, Mitsuhiko?!
!اخرس! لديك مشكلة معي يا ميتسوهيكو؟
Stop it, Genta-kun!
!توقف يا غينتا-كن
I gotta go, I'm really busy!
!أنا مشغول لذا سأذهب
Wait, Conan-kun!
!انتظر يا كونان-كن
Dang it...
تبّاً
I'll never find those men in black if things keep up like this.
لن أجد الرجال بالرداء الأسود على هذا النحو أبداً
Just be patient, Shinichi.
تحلَّ بالصبر يا شينتشي
Think what would happen if you rushed things
فكّر بما سيحصل إن استعجلت
I know, I know.
أفهم ذلك
It would put not just me but all the people around me in real danger.
،سيكون جميع من حولي في خطر ليس أنا فقط
Oh, yes! Ran-kun came by yesterday.
بالمناسبة، أتت ران-كن بالأمس
She did?
ران؟
Shinichi didn't come to school again today.
لم يأت شينتشي للمدرسة مُجدداً اليوم
And it doesn't look like he's been home either...
ولا يبدو أنّه عاد لمنزله أيضاً
I think I'll call the police...
...سأتّصل بالشرطة
Wait!
!انتظري
I'm sure he's just working on another one of his strange cases...
أنا متأكد أنّه يعمل على إحدى قضاياه الغريبة فقط
Don't worry. He'll be back home soon enough, I'm sure of it.
،لا تقلقي، سيعود في أقرب فرصة أنا على يقين
I've got her convinced for the time being, but how long can we keep this up?
أقنعتُها في الوقت الراهن، لكن إلى متى يمكننا مواصلة هذا؟
Ran...
...ران
Oh, that's right!
!صحيح
I made something you'll find useful for your cases.
صنعتُ شيئاً سيفيدك في قضاياك
This is a Voice-Altering Bow Tie!
!إنّها ربطة العنق المعدّلة للصوت
"Voice-Altering"?
معدّلة للصوت؟
Turn the dial on the back and you can make all kinds of voices.
أدر القرص في الخلف وستتمكن من إصدار مختلف الأصوات
You can sound like an old man, a child, a man, and even a woman.
صوت رجل مُسن، طفل، رجل بالغ وحتّى امرأة
I'm certain it'll come in handy at some point!
سيفيدك في وقت ما حتماً
I doubt that a detective agency would have much use for this...
لا أظن سأستعمله كثيراً في وكالة التحرّي تلك
So, that's Conan-kun's house!
!ذاك منزل كونان-كن إذاً
We have no choice, we're gonna force him to be our friend!
!لا خيار لدينا، سنجبره ليصبح صديقنا
That's...
...إنّها
The Mori Detective Agency is closed today. If you've got a job for me...
،وكالة موري للتحري مغلقة اليوم ...إن كان لديك طلب عمل
...come back... tomorrow...
...فعد... غداً
Oh my god! It's you!
!أنت... أيمكن
Yoko Okino!
!أوكينو يوكو
That's right.
أجل
No way! What would a celebrity be doing here?
لا يمكن! لمَ قد تأتي فنّانة شهيرة هنا؟
Actually, I want to hire you...
...أريد طلب خدمتك في الواقع
You appear to be troubled, my dear.
يبدو أنّ هناك أمراً يضايقك سيّدتي
Yes...
أجل
Who the heck are you?
من أنت؟
What?!
!ماذا؟
Somebody's spying on you?!
يتجسّس أحدهم عليك؟
The furniture's been moved whenever I come home,
أجد الأثاث في غير مكانه عند عودتي للبيت
somebody's been sending me candid photos they took of me,
وأستلم صوراً مُلتقطة خلسة من أحدهم
and I've been getting anonymous phone calls everyday!
!بالإضافة إلى اتّصالات مجهولة يومياً
How dare they!
!كيف يجرؤ الوغد؟
If at all possible, we'd like you to look into it quietly.
نريدك أن تتحرى بهدوءٍ لو أمكن
Who're you?
من أنت؟
Oh, I'm Yamagishi, her manager.
أنا مديرها، اسمي ياماغيشي
Her manager?
مديرها؟
Very well. I will investigate as discreetly as possible.
حسناً، سأتحرّى بكتمان قدر المستطاع
I'll need your address and phone number here.
دوّني عنوانك ورقم هاتفك هنا من فضلك
Okay.
حسناً
And if you could autograph this too...
...كما توقيعك هنا لو أمكن
Don't forget to write "To Kogoro"...
"لا تنسي كتابة "إلى كوغورو-سان
Now that the great detective Kogoro Mori is on the case,
بما أنّ القضية بيد المتحرّي العظيم موري كوغورو الآن
you have nothing to fear!
!لا شيء لتخافيه
Can I come too?
أيمكننا مرافقتكم؟
I've always wanted to see a celebrity's home.
لطالما أردتُ رؤية منزل فنّان شهير
Don't you agree, Conan-kun?
صحيح يا كونان-كن؟
Yeah.
أجل
Just don't be getting in the way! Got it?!
إيّاكما واعتراض العمل، مفهوم؟
We won't!
!حسناً
So, this is it?!
!هنا إذاً؟
This is exactly the kind of place I thought Yoko Okino might live!
!مسكن يليق بأوكينو يوكو-سان حقّاً
Hey, not so loud!
!لا ترفع صوتك
Nobody's supposed to know she lives here, it's a secret.
يُفترض أن تكون إقامتها هنا سرّاً
The 25th floor, was it?
الطابق 25 إذاً؟
Yoko-chan in the flesh... Awesome!
!يوكو-تشان دون سواها! مذهل
We definitely have to make friends with Conan-kun!
علينا أن نجعل كونان-كن صديقنا !مهما كلّف الأمر
Agreed.
أتفق
It's so pretty!
جميل
Come on inside...
تفضّلوا بالدخول
What's the matter, Yoko?
ما الخطب يا يوكو؟
You guys!
!أنتم
This is...
...إنّه
Is everyone all right?
أأنتم بخير؟
Jeez...
يا إلهي
I see.
فهمت
So, he had already been murdered by the time you got back?
كان مقتولاً بوقت عودتك إذاً؟
Yes.
أجل
And the person with you at the time was...
...ومن كان رفقتك
...was I, Kogoro Mori, Inspector Megure!
!أنا سيّدي المفتش ميغوري، موري كوغورو
Why him, of all people?
يا إلهي، لمَ هو بالذات؟
It's just like old times!
!يشعرني هذا بالحنين
Remember all those cases we worked on together?!
تذكر القضايا التي عملنا عليها سويّاً في الأيام الخوالي؟
Yes. And thanks to you, most of them went unsolved!
أجل، وأُغلقت معظمها دون أن تُحلّ بسببك
It certainly is hot in here.
المكان حارّ هنا
Do you always have the heater on this high?
أترفعين درجة جهاز التدفئة لهذا الحد دوماً؟
No.
كلا
And I'm sure I turned it off before I left.
كما أنّي أطفأته قبل مغادرتي حتماً
That's odd.
هذا غريب
That isn't the only thing that's odd, Inspector.
ليس ذلك الغريب فقط حضرة المفتش
They're very faint, but there are damp spots all around the body.
إنّها طفيفة، لكن هناك بقع رطبة حول الجثة
And this chair is the only thing still standing,
كما ذاك الكرسيّ هو الشيء الوحيد الواقف
while everything else in the room has been thrown about.
بينما كلّ ما سواه في الغرفة مطروح
And this heat...
...وهذه الحرارة
Was it done to disguise the time of death?
أكان الهدف منها العبث بوقت الوفاة؟
Kids shouldn't get in the way!
!يجب ألّا يتدخل الأطفال
That means you!
!الكلام لك
Have you determined the cause of death?
هل حددتم سبب الموت؟
It would seem this knife was the cause.
يبدو أنّها هذه السكّين
Does that knife belong to you?
أتخصك تلك السكين؟
Y-Yes...
أجل
You can't honestly suspect Yoko?
أتشكّون بيوكو حقاً؟
Have you seen the victim before?
أسبق ورأيتما الضحية؟
Um, I'd have to take a closer look...
أحتاج لإلقاء نظرة أقرب
So, have you seen him before?
أرأيتماه قبلاً إذاً؟
I'm sorry, I guess we haven't.
آسف، لم نلتقه قبلاً
Right, Yoko?
صحيح يا يوكو؟
Yes...
أ-أجل
I'm sure I saw him...
...رأيتُه بالفعل
What was that? What did he pick up?
ما كان ذلك؟ ما الذي أخذه؟
Don't mind me.
لا تبالوا لي
A strand of hair?
خيط شعر؟
Why would her manager try to hide this?
لمَ قد يحاول مديرها إخفاء هذا؟
Could the murderer have been...?
...أيمكن أنّ القاتل
The murder took place while the door was locked.
وقعت الجريمة في غرفة مغلقة
Which means the murderer was the apartment's resident.
مما يعني أنّ القاتل كان ساكناً في هذه الشقة
No! I could never kill anyone!
!مُحال! لا يمكنني قتل شخص أبداً
She's telling the truth, Inspector.
!إنّها محقة حضرة المفتش
Just because she has a key doesn't mean...
...مجرد امتلاكها للمفتاح لا يعني
Don't people usually have a spare key?
ألا يملك الناس مفاتيح احتياطية عادةً؟
Yeah!
!بلى
Hey now, stay out of this!
لا تتدخلوا
Um, Yamagishi-san has my spare key.
يملك ياماغيشي-سان مفتاحاً احتياطياً
That's it!
!وجدتُها
Yamagishi! You're the murderer!
!ياماغيشي! أنتَ القاتل
Yamagishi!
!ياماغيشي
Yoko gave you the cold shoulder so you took it out on him, didn't you?!
رفضت يوكو مشاعرك، لذا صببتَ جام !غضبك عليه، أليس كذلك؟
Hey, now. Where's the proof that she didn't do it?
رويدك، ما هو دليل براءتها؟
Such a beautiful young woman would never do anything like that!
فتاة حسناء ببهائها لا يمكن أن !تقدم على أمر كهذا أبداً
I see...
هكذا إذاً
Morons.
أحمق
Yes, I did have her spare key, but I lost it 2 or 3 days ago...
،كان لديّ مفتاح بديل بالفعل لكني فقدته قبل عدّة أيام
Stop lying!
!لا تكذب
I'm not! I was in the dressing room at the TV station.
إنّها الحقيقة! كنتُ في غرفة تبديل الملابس في محطة التلفاز
I can vouch for him, he told me about it!
!أخبرني ذلك أيضاً، إنّها الحقيقة
Well, if that's what Yoko-san says, then...
...حسناً، إن كنتِ تشهدين بذلك يا يوكو-سان فإذاً
I get the feeling that we're still lacking something really important
أشعر أن شيئاً مهماً ينقصنا
that could explain everything here...
بإمكانه توضيح كلّ شيء هنا
An earring?!
قرط أذن؟
Hey, Inspector, under that sofa...
...مفتّش، يوجد تحت تلك الأريكة
You kids stay out of this!
!ليبتعد الأطفال
Dang it, they all ignore me...
تبّاً، كلهم يتجاهلونني
That's it! This thing!
!وجدتُها، هذا الشيء
I'll just set it to an adult's voice, and...
...سأعدّله لصوت بالغ و
Inspector, there's something beneath the sofa.
حضرة المفتش، هناك شيء تحت الأريكة
What's this?
ما هذا؟
An earring...
...قرط
That's Yuko-san's...
...إنّه يخص يُوكو-سان
Yuko-san?
يُوكو-سان؟
Yuko Ikezawa-san. She debuted the same time I did.
إيكيزاوا يُوكو-سان التي بدأت مسيرتها الفنية في نفس الوقت معي
I heard that she was upset that Yoko got her role in a drama series...
سمعتُ أنّها كانت مستاءة لحصول يوكو على دورها في أحد المسلسلات
Now I've got it!
!حللتُ الأمر الآن
The murderer was Yuko Ikezawa! Arrest her!
!المجرمة هي إيكيزاوا يُوكو! اعتقلوها
Isn't that right, Inspector?
صحيح سيّدي المفتش؟
We'll have to go to the station--
...حسناً، علينا الذهاب للمركز
No, let's have her come here for questioning!
!كلا، لنطلب قدومها هنا للاستجواب
You heard the inspector! Hurry!
!كما سمعتم! أسرعوا
Yes, sir!
!حاضر
Yuko Ikezawa did it! There's no doubt about it!
!المجرمة هي إيكيزاوا يُوكو! لا شكّ في ذلك
Judging from the scene of the crime, the murderer must be Yoko Okino!
بناءً على مسرح الجريمة، لا بد أن تكون المجرمة هي أوكينو يوكو
The manager's inexplicable action...
...تصرّف المدير مجهول الدوافع
And the odd marks left behind in the room...
...كما العلامات الغريبة المتروكة في الغرفة
All the pieces are here.
كلّ القطع هنا
The question is how to put them together...
بقيت مشكلة جمعها فقط
You've got to be kidding me!
!لا تمازحوني
The murder took place in Yoko's place.
وقعت الجريمة في شقّة يوكو
She's the one you should suspect.
لذا يُفترض أن تكون هي المشتبه بها
Yuko-san...
...يُوكو-سان
I've never been here before now. I'm innocent.
لم يسبق لي أن أتيت هنا، أنا بريئة
Then what was this doing here?!
كيف تفسرين وجود هذا إذًا؟
I thought I lost that somewhere! I'm glad you found it!
،ظننتُ أني أضعته في مكان ما !يسرّني عثوركم عليه
It doesn't stop with the earring.
لا يتوقف الأمر عند القرط
The superintendent also said that he's seen someone who looks like you!
قال مشرف المبنى أنّه رأى شخصاً يشبهك
Someone who looks like me? This is ridiculous.
شخص يشبهني؟ يا للسخافة
I'm borrowing your bathroom.
سأذهب للحمام
Hold it! I'm not done yet!
!انتظري! لم أنه كلامي
You never give up, do you?!
!يكفي
You think I'm the murderer just because of an earring?!
!أتعتقد أنّي المجرمة لقرط أذن فقط؟
I'm really busy, you know!
!أنا مشغولة
Not nearly as busy as little Miss Popular Celebrity, though...
لكن ليس بقدر الآنسة رقم 1 في الشعبية
But if the media gets wind of this, your image'll take a nosedive!
!لكن إن تسلل هذا الخبر للإعلام، فستتلطخ سمعتك
Maybe you'll lose as much work as I have!
فقد تصبحين متفرّغة تماماً من قلّة الأعمال
How dare you threaten her!
!كيف تجرؤين على تهديدها؟
They both look exactly the same from behind...
يبدوان بنفس المظهر من الوراء
And how did she know...
...كما كيف عرفتْ
Hey, grownups!
!يا عمَّاه
Shut up, boy!
!اخرس يا فتى
What!?
!ماذا؟
Why, you...!
!أنت
Don't get in the way of their investigation, Conan-kun.
لا تتدخل في التحقيق يا كونان-كن
But if Shinichi were here, he'd easily solve this case.
لكن لو كان شينتشي هنا، كان ليحلّ هذه القضية بسهولة حتماً
Where could that mystery geek have gone?
أين ذهب مهووس التحرّي ذاك؟
Don't worry! He'll be back, I'm sure of it!
!سيعود قريباً بالتأكيد! لا تقلقي
I mean, maybe...
...أقصد، ربما
What do I have to say for you to understand?!
ماذا عليّ أن أقول لتفهم؟
I already told you I've never been here before!
أخبرتك لم يسبق لي القدوم هنا
That's a pretty weird lighter, isn't it?
إنّها قدّاحة غريبة
How did you know this was a lighter if you've never been here before?
كيف عرفتِ أنّها قدّاحة مع أنّه لم يسبق لك القدوم هنا؟
Yes. Care to explain how you knew?
صحيح، كيف عرفتِ؟
I know someone who has one just like it.
توجد واحدة مثلها في منزل شخص أعرفه
And where does this someone live?
وأين منزل ذاك الشخص؟
Well, um...
...في الواقع
Where's the bathroom?
أين الحمام؟
I've never been here before, so I don't know where it is.
لم أزر المكان قبلاً، فلا أعرف أين هو
Eh? It's in the hallway...
...ماذا؟ إنّه في الرواق
Come to think of it, you knew where the bathroom was, too!
!صحيح، عرفتِ مكان الحمام أيضاً
Which is because you, Yuko Ikezawa, are the murderer!
!ذلك لأنّك القاتلة يا إيكيزاوا يُوكو
You killed that man in this apartment to create a big scandal around Yoko-san!
قتلتِ ذاك الرجل في هذه الشقّة للتسبب بفضيحة تضرّ بيوكو-سان
I didn't.
!كلا
I didn't! I didn't kill him!
!كلا! لم أقتله
All I did was defend myself when he suddenly attacked me!
!دافعتُ عن نفسي عندما هاجمني فجأةً فقط
I'll admit it, I did sneak in here several times
أعترف أنّي تسللت هنا عدّة مرات
using the spare key I stole from the dressing room.
باستعمال المفتاح البديل الذي سرقته من غرفة تبديل الملابس
I wanted to find something, anything that could cause a scandal!
!أردتُ العثور على أي شيء يتسبّب بفضيحة لها
But when I came in this afternoon, that man suddenly showed up!
لكن عندما أتيتُ ظهيرة اليوم، ظهر ذاك الرجل فجأةً
I defended myself with all of my strength...
!دافعتُ عن نفسي بكلّ قوّتي
...and then escaped as quickly as I could!
!ثمّ هربت بأسرع ما يمكن
I said I didn't kill him!
!أخبرتك أنّي لم أقتله
Inspector!
!حضرة المفتش
We've learned the identity of the victim.
وجدنا هويّة الضحية
Akiyoshi Fujie, 22 years old.
فوجي آكيوشي، 22 عاماً
Upon graduating from Konan High School,
بعد تخرّجه من ثانوية كونان
he began working for Kakubeni Corporation.
بدأ العمل في شركة كاكوبيني
Konan High School...
...ثانوية كونان
Isn't that your old high school, Yoko-san?
ألم تكن هذه ثانويتك القديمة يا يوكو-سان؟
It's just a coincidence!
!مجرد مصادفة
Isn't that right, Yoko?
صحيح يا يوكو؟
I... I know him!
!أنا... أنا أعرفه
No, I didn't just know him, he was my high school boyfriend!
ليس معرفةً فقط، كان حبيبي في الثانوية
What?!
!ماذا؟
Yoko!
!يوكو
I'm sorry, Yamagishi-san. I can't hide it.
آسفة يا ياماغيشي-سان، لا أستطيع إخفاء الأمر
Don't tell me you did this to break up with your old flame!
أيمكن أنك أقدمتِ على هذا !لقطع علاقتك القديمة؟
No, I didn't!
!كلا
After all, he was the one who dumped me.
هو من هجرني في نهاية المطاف
Who is it?
من؟
Who's the murderer?!
من القاتل؟
Yoko Okino?
أوكينو يوكو؟
Yuko Ikezawa?
إيكيزاوا يُوكو؟
Yamagishi, the manager?
أم المدير ياماغيشي؟
Darn it...
تبّاً
We're still missing something we need to make any deductions!
!لا يزال ينقصنا شيء لإكمال الاستنتاج
What is it? What are we missing?
ماذا؟ ما الذي ينقصنا؟
A dent in the floor?
انبعاج في الأرض؟
Wait a second...
...لحظة
Even though the room's in shambles, this chair is the only thing left standing.
الكرسي هو الشيء الوحيد الواقف مع أنّ الغرفة في فوضى
And this room's exceptionally high temperature...
...كما حرارة الغرفة المرتفعة جداً
The water splotches left around the body...
...بقع الماء حول الجثّة
The hair in the corpse's hand?
والشعر في يد الجثة؟
A-ha! That's it!
!أجل! وجدتُها
I've finally solved the puzzle!
!حللتُ الأحجية أخيراً
The murderer...
...القاتل
...is you, Yamagishi!
!هو أنت يا ياماغيشي
You saw him as an obstacle
اعتبرتَه عقبة
because he was capable of starting a scandal around Yoko-san!
لأنّ بإمكانه التسبب بفضيحة ليوكو-سان
Then you ran into him while he was hiding in here
واجهته في الغرفة بينما كان يختبئ
and proceeded to kill him!
!ثم قتلته
No!
!كلا
Yamagishi-san isn't the murderer!
!ياماغيشي-سان ليس القاتل
What a nice nap...
نمت كثيراً
You're conscious again, Genta-kun!
أفقت مُجدداً يا غينتا-كن؟
Where's the bathroom?
أين الحمام؟
That way.
هناك
You're the only one left who could be the murderer!
لم يبق أحد يمكن أن !يكون المجرم سواك
Forgive me, old man!
!آسف يا عمّ
Fess up! You'll feel better!
!اعترف! ستشعر بالراحة
Oh no!
!تبّاً
In that case...
...إذاً
Now then, I'll just set it to his voice, and...
...حسنٌ، سأضبطها لصوته و
Which is what I would like to say, but that isn't the case.
ذلك ما أقول، لكنها ليست الحقيقة
Yamagishi-san.
ياماغيشي-سان
If you really asked me to help you so that I would discover the body,
لو طلبتَ خدماتي كي أجد الجثة
you would have also prepared something to prove your innocence.
فكنتَ لتحضّر دليل براءة لك أيضاً
Yoko-san, the same goes for you,
ينطبق ذلك عليك أيضاً يا يوكو-سان
especially since the 1st person to suspect would be the apartment's tenant.
فأنتِ المشتبه بها الأولى لكونك مالكة الشقّة
So, then the murderer... is Yuko Ikezawa!
!القاتل إذاً... إيكيزاوا يُوكو
Now wait just a minute!
!تمهل
She didn't do it either.
ليست هي أيضاً
Even if she did commit the murder in the heat of the moment,
،لو قتلتَه أثناء تشابكهما
she wouldn't have told us she ran into him.
ما كانت لتخبرنا بلقائها المفاجئ به
But what you're saying is...
...لكن ما تقوله
Yes, these are only educated guesses at most.
أجل، كلّها تخمينات حالياً
They don't hold up as proof that the three of them are innocent.
لا يمكن أن تكون برهان براءة لأيّ منهم
But there is evidence to support it.
لكن يوجد دليل يدعم ذلك
Yamagishi-san.
ياماغيشي-سان
You pretended to slip and then removed strands of hair from the body.
تظاهرتَ بالانزلاق ثم أزلتَ خيوط شعر من الجثة
What?!
!ماذا؟
I knew it! I knew you were the killer!
!أنتَ القاتل بالفعل إذاً
You're wrong.
ليس صحيحاً
The man was stabbed in the back,
طُعن الرجل من الخلف
but he was holding the stabber's hair in his hands.
لكنه كان يحمل شعرات طاعنه في يده
Don't you find that a bit odd?
ألا تجدون الأمر غريباً؟
Now that you mention it...
معك حقّ
The one responsible set it all up to look like a murder...
...رتّب الفاعل الأمر كي يبدو كجريمة قتل
As if he was killed by Yoko-san herself...
كما لو أنّه قُتل بواسطة يوكو-سان
"Like a murder"?
يبدو كجريمة قتل؟
You don't mean...
...أ-أتقصد
That's right.
...صحيح
The killer is none other than...
...القاتل
...the late Fujie-san himself!
!هو المتوفى فوجي-سان نفسه
A suicide?!
!انتحار؟
Nonsense! How could he stab himself in the back with a knife?!
لا يمكن! كيف يطعن نفسه بسكّين من الوراء؟
It's a simple trick involving ice.
إنّها حيلة بسيطة تعتمد على الثلج
He set the heater on high, took hairs from Yoko-san's brush,
رفع حرارة جهاز التدفئة، وأخذ شعر يوكو-سان من فرشاتها
then stood up on a chair and fell back onto a knife
ثمّ وقف على كرسي ورمى نفسه على السكّين
that was held in place by a block of ice.
كانت مُثبّتة بمكعّب ثلجي
You'll find the indentation mark made by the knife's handle
ستجد انبعاجاً سببه مِقبض السكّين
near where the body was.
بقرب مكان الجثة
The ice shattered and later melted because of the high heat.
تكسر الثلج وذاب لاحقاً بفعل الحرارة
However, Fujie-san tried too hard to frame her.
لكن بالغ فوجي-سان في محاولة إدانتها
The hair?
الشعر؟
Yes.
أجل
When Yamagishi-san saw it,
عندما رآه ياماغيشي-سان
he tried to hide it because he thought Yoko-san had indeed killed him.
حاول إخفاءه لاعتقاده أنّ يوكو-سان قتلته حقّاً
But why would Fujie-kun do something like this?
لكن لمَ قد يقوم فوجي-كن بشيء كهذا؟
I would think that it was because he still loved you.
لأنّه كان لا يزال يحبك غالباً
Didn't you realize that the two of you look exactly the same from behind?
ألم تدركي أنكما متشابهتان تماماً من الوراء؟
So, he mistook Yuko-san for Yoko-san and attacked-
لذا ظنّ أن يُوكو-سان هي يوكو-سان وهاجمها
No. He tried to talk to her.
كلا، حاول الكلام معها
Not realizing he was talking to Yuko-san and not Yoko-san,
لكنه لم يدرك أنها كانت يُوكو-سان وليس يوكو-سان
he was completely shocked when she resisted him,
فصُدم تماماً عندما قاومتْه
and the feelings of his love being driven to the wall turned into despair and hatred.
وسقطت مشاعر الحب المجروحة لفوهة اليأس والكراهية
But he dumped me! Why would he do that?
لكنه من هجرني! لمَ قد يقوم بذلك؟
No, that's not the truth, Yoko...
ليست هذه الحقيقة يا يوكو
The truth is, I asked him to break up with you.
كنتُ من طلب منه هجرك في الواقع
How could you?
...كـ-كيف
Inspector!
!حضرة المفتش
What is it?
ما الأمر؟
We've found a diary in the late Fujie-san's house.
وجدنا مذكرة يوميات في منزل المتوفى فوجي-سان
What?!
!ماذا؟
The diary was filled with his pain.
كانت المذكرة مليئة بألمه
How even after they broke up,
وتحكي عجزه عن نسيانها
he was unable to forget about her, so he went to see her.
بعد انفصالهما، فذهب لرؤيتها
He hoped she would end her career as a celebrity and come back to him.
كان يأمل أن تترك مهنتها كفنّانة وترجع له
All he wanted to do was clear up the misunderstandings.
كلّ ما أراده هو توضيح ما أُسيئ فهمه
The last thing he wrote was that he couldn't live like this any longer.
آخر كلماته كانت أنّه لا يستطيع العيش هكذا أكثر
It would appear this was a tragic story that consisted of lies,
...يبدو أنّها كانت مأساة مُحاكة بالأكاذيب
misunderstandings, and coincidence.
والمغالطات والصُدف
Hot!
!حارّ
Mori-kun! You were right!
!موري-كن! تحليلك في محله
I've changed my mind about you, "Great Detective"!
!تغيّرت نظرتي تجاهك أيّها المتحري العظيم
I'm exhausted...
أشعر بالإعياء
It was a little scary, but I've never been that excited before!
كان الأمر مخيفاً قليلاً، لكن لم يسبق وشعرتُ بذاك الحماس
I think if we make friends with Conan-kun,
،أظن إن صادقنا كونان-كن
we'll get to experience lots more thrills and suspense!
!سنمرّ بالكثير من التشويق والإثارة
Alright then! We've gotta get Conan-kun to be our friend!
حسنٌ، علينا جعل كونان-كن يصبح صديقنا في هذه الحالة
Yeah!
!أجل
She's so strong!
إنّها قويّة
Already back on her feet after all that happened...
وقفت مجدداً بعد كلّ ما حصل
I could never do that. I could never be as strong as Yoko-san...
...لا يمكنني أن أكون قويّةً مثلك يا يوكو-سان
I can't even sleep at night with Shinichi gone...
لا أستطيع حتّى ذالنوم ليلاً في غياب شينتشي
I'm really hopeless...
لا أمل مني حقاً
It's strange.
غريب
Shinichi has been missing for a week now...
...شينتشي غائب لأسبوع الآن
Something must have happened to him!
!حصل أمرٌ ما له حتماً
But nothing like that would ever happen to Shinichi!
!لكن... لا يمكن أن يحلّ أمر كذاك بشينتشي
Shinichi... Come back soon!
!شينتشي... عُد سريعاً! شينتشي
Hello, Mori Detective--
...مرحباً، معك وكالة موري
Ran.
ران
It's me.
إنّه أنا، أعرفتِني؟
Shinichi?
شينتشي؟
I figured you might be crying because you're worried about me.
ظننتكِ غارقة في دموعكِ قلقاً عليّ
Yeah, right. Why would I be crying?
أحمق! لمَ قد أبكي؟
Where are you right now, Shinichi?
أين أنت الآن يا شينتشي؟
I was asked to take a sort of dangerous case...
كُلفت بقضيّة معقدة
I'll come back home once I've taken care of it.
سأعود فورما أنتهي منها
So, don't worry.
لذا لا تقلقي عليّ
I'm sorry, Ran.
آسف يا ران
When I return to my normal body, I'll let you hear it...
سأسمعك إيّاه عندما أعود لجسدي الطبيعي
My real voice...
...صوتي الحقيقي
My real feelings...
كما مشاعري الحقيقية
What do you think these drawings could be?
ما هذه الرسمات برأيكم؟
I'll bet it's a treasure map!
!إنّها خريطة كنز حتماً
It's time for some treasure hunting!
!لنذهب في رحلة بحث عن كنز يا رفاق
From this day forth, we'll be known as the Junior Detective Club!
!نحن نادي المتحرّيين الصغار من اليوم فصاعداً
I'm gonna use my share of the treasure to eat every gourmet meal in the world!
سأستعمل حصّتي من الكنز لأكل !كلّ وجبة في العالم
What about you, Conan-kun?
ماذا عنك يا كونان-كن؟
I'll save it, I guess...
...أ-أظنني سأدّخره
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
The Case of the Coded City Map.
قضيّة خريطة المدينة المشفرة
Next Conan's Hint:
:تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Neon Sign.
لافتة نيون
Will you be able to crack the code in the next episode?
هل ستستطيعون حلّ الشفرة الحلقة القادمة؟